# 福建·厦门
Xiamen, Fujian
# 今天我们到的是厦门的
We are around Bashi seafood market
# 八市海鲜市场这一边
of Xiamen today
# 这边的海鲜水产真的是让人看花了眼
There is plenty of seafood
# 各种鱼 虾 蟹啊 贝类 应有尽有
Plenty types of fish, shrimp, and shellfish
# 因为不认识 很多情况下
As we can't recognize the kinds, in many cases
# 我们都是这样 大眼瞪着小眼
we can only stare at each other awkwardly like this
# 不过我们今天不打算吃海鲜
However, we don’t plan to have seafood today
# 打算找一些比较特别的小吃吧
We plan to find some special street food
# 这边有种食物叫做 五香还挺吸引我的
There is a street food called "wuxiang" (five-spice) roll, which is quite attractive
# 看看前面有没有
Let's see if there is any ahead
# 你好 我想问一下 是这个是叫五香吗
Hello, is this called “wuxiang” (five spiced)
# 是的
Yes
# 这个是什么做的
What's that made of?
# 猪肉 洋葱
Pork, onion
# 猪肉和洋葱
Pork and onion
# 外面包的是什么
What's the wrapper outside?
# 豆皮
Tofu skin
# 多少钱
How much?
# 4块钱
4 yuan
# 买10条
I want 10
# 来6条吧
six
# 哎呀 来6条吧
Aiya, I'll have six
# 给我拿两条
Can I have two?
# 切吗？
Cut it?
# 切
Cut it
# 谢谢
Thank you
# 穿过拥挤的人潮 我买到了五香卷
Going through the crowd, I bought the spiced rolls
# 五香卷给我放进去的时候
She digged two holes on the box
# 还在盒子上面戳了两个孔
When she put the spiced rolls in
# 所以我的手能够感受到刚炸出来
So I can feel the hot air
# 五香的这种热气
of freshly fried spiced rolls
# 走了十多分钟 总算走出来了
10 minutes later, we have finally moved outside
# 我们要去尝一尝自己买的五香啦
We are going to taste the spiced rolls we ordered
# 刚才买五香的时候 旁边的阿姨说
When buying them, the auntie told me
# 这个五香在过年的时候
during Chinese New Year
# 能够卖一万条
they can sell 10,000 rolls
# 一天一万条
10,000 rolls every day
# 咱们呢 只是买了两条来解解馋
For us, we bought only two to have a taste
# 还没有打开盖子 你就能闻到这个香味
You can smell the fragrance even without opening the box
# 感觉是这种油炸的香味 还带点蒜味
Feels like the fragrance of fried food, and a bit of garlic
# 打开了
opened
# 让我们一睹尊容
Let's have a look of its appearance
# 五香看起来 颜色是偏向于深褐色的
The color of the spiced roll is kind of dark brown
# 通过它的横截面 你能够看到
Looking at the cross section, you can see
# 它里面包裹的肉馅还有洋葱
it is stuffed with meat and onion
# 它这个五香外皮是带有点褶皱的
The wrapper is a little wrinkled
# 所以说 看上去很像烧腊 烧鹅的外貌
so it looks quite similar to Cantonese BBQ, roasted goose
# 这个五香一口咬下去是这种
As you take a bite of the spiced roll
# 甜甜糯糯的口感
the mouthfeel is sweet and mashy
# 它这个甜 不是说没有咸味
It's not purely sweet without salt
# 而是甜味占了上风
but instead, it's mostly sweet
# 这种甜味是夹带着洋葱的甜味
The sweetness also contains the sweetness of onions
# 门口的小姐姐说 这里面用的肉馅
The sis at the entrance said that
# 没有一点肥的
the meat stuffing here is lean only without any fat
# 经过油炸之后 吃起来
After deep frying,
# 也不会觉得有那么油腻
it doesn't feel very greasy
# 但是吃多了 还是会觉得
You might still feel a little greasy
# 有些油腻的
if you eat too much
# 你看 咱们吃五香会觉得它有点甜
You see, we feel it is a little too sweet when we eat it
# 但是我看很多老人
However, I saw a lot of elderly people
# 都会在这个五香上 再抹一些甜辣酱
Add sweet and spicy sauce on top
# 这个口感 可能会更符合他的口味吧
They probably prefer a mouthfeel like that
# 在这里 你不能走很快
You should not walk too fast there
# 因为在不经意间
Because inadvertently
# 你可能就错过了很多的好吃的
you might have missed a lot of delicious food
# 关 注 雪 鱼 探 店
Subscribe
# 因为戴了咬合垫
As I'm wearing a bite plate
# 我小口抿的吃饭方式
the way I eat by small bites
# 受到伙伴的嘲笑
is mocked by the team
# 于是 摄影师决定亲自上阵
So, the cameraman decided to take the role
# 来说一说 它是什么样的味道
and tell how it tastes like
# 问题：什么样的感受
Question: what's the feeling?
# 黏黏糯糯的 一口下去都是肉
Sticky and mashy, full of meat in the mouth
# 听到没 甜甜糯糯的 一口下去都是肉
Did you hear that? Sticky and mashy, full of meat in the mouth
# 还有吗？
Anything else?
# 不知道什么味 再给我吃一个
Can't tell the taste. Give me another one
# 再见
Goodbye